"The Stranger I Met" Episode 5
'내가 만난 낯선 사람' 5회
(Wu Gang Dumu)
(우강두무)
(Kyung Gi Joo)
(주경기)
"A Stranger I Met"
"내가 만난 낯선 사람"
Two days before the first murder
첫 번째 살인 이틀 전
One of the three suspects has been arrested
용의자 3명 중 1명 검거
the other two
나머지 두 개
Nothing special yet
아직 특별한 것은 없습니다
When everything is so chaotic
모든 것이 너무 혼란스러울 때
She is coming
그녀가오고있다
He is the first victim of Wu Zongri's serial murder case
그는 우종리 연쇄살인사건의 첫 번째 피해자 이다.
she
그녀
The teacher who will be with you throughout the month
한 달 내내 함께 해줄 선생님
It’s teacher Li Zhouying
리저우잉 선생님이에요
- Seoul National University.. - Where..
- 서울대학교.. - 어디..
- Major in Korean Literature - You must have read it
- 국문학 전공 - 꼭 읽어보셨을 거예요
What's wrong?
뭐가 문제 야?
I got a call from the principal
교장한테 전화가 왔어.
I couldn’t make an appointment to meet with teacher Li Zhouying.
나는 Li Zhouying 선생님과의 만남 약속을 잡을 수 없었습니다 .
That's definitely what I know.
내가 아는 것은 확실히 그것이다.
That day I chose her at first sight
그날 나는 첫눈에 그녀를 선택했다
as my beautiful first death
나의 아름다운 첫 죽음으로
Will that girl die?
그 여자 죽나요?
how do you know?
어떻게 알아?
This is a case that has not happened yet
아직까지 일어나지 않은 사건이에요
Now how do we know this?
이제 우리는 이것을 어떻게 알 수 있습니까?
(Part 5 – A Confession)
(5부 – 고백)
what did you just say?
너 방금 뭐라고 했어?
Article (5)
제5조
Isn't it a coincidence that we meet here ?
우리가 여기서 만난 것은 우연이 아닌가 ?
if all this is true
이 모든 것이 사실이라면
tonight
오늘 밤
Well, two days before that school teacher died
음, 그 학교 선생님이 돌아가시기 이틀 전에
He said there was a case where he suddenly disappeared
갑자기 사라진 사례도 있다고 하더군요
Fortunately, I was discovered by the villagers.
다행히 마을 사람들에게 발견됐어요 .
Because I know I've lost my way
내가 길을 잃었다는 걸 알기 때문에
Although it was just a small incident in the end, in fact
결국은 작은 사건이었지만 사실
It seems like someone is being chased
누군가 쫓기고 있는 것 같아
where was found
어디서 발견됐나
Do you know where it is?
거기가 어디인지 아시나요?
River bank
강둑
If it's close to a grocery store, it should be around here
식료품점 근처에 있다면 이 근처에 있을 거예요
Well
잘
Li Zhuying
리 주잉
-Teacher- No, I'm not
-선생님- 아니요, 아니에요
ha
하아
What's your job?
당신의 직업은 무엇입니까?
Are you half crazy and want to die?
반쯤 미쳤고 죽고 싶나요?
It’s Teacher Yin Hyejun again, is it you?
또 인혜준 선생님이시죠?
ha
하아
Destroying it once is not enough
한 번 파괴하는 것만으로는 충분하지 않습니다.
Do you want to destroy it two or three times again and again?
두세 번이고 또 파괴하고 싶나요?
Gominsu was released, right?
고민수가 풀려났죠?
Why?
왜?
Just followed the order
그냥 순서대로 따랐어요
Very responsible words
매우 책임감있는 말
Because doing work this way
이런 식으로 일을 하니까
This is a one-time error
일회성 오류입니다.
Now you have to accept this, Badang Badan
이제는 받아들여야 해 바당바단
if we are unlucky
우리가 운이 좋지 않다면
Because of the person you released today
오늘 풀어준 사람 때문에
Someone's life may be in danger again
누군가의 생명이 다시 위험에 빠질 수 있습니다
Are you fat now?
이제 뚱뚱해졌나요?
It's just that guy again
또 그 사람이구나
What did that guy do?
그 사람은 무엇을 했나요?
You have nothing to say, right?
할 말이 없잖아요 ?
I know for a fact that letting him go was the worst idea
나는 그를 놓아주는 것이 최악의 생각이라는 사실을 알고 있습니다
Be sure to answer the question
질문에 꼭 답해주세요
- Gominsu Is it hot now? - I have no idea
- 고민수 지금 더워요? - 모르겠어요
i don't know what
나는 무엇을 모른다
Who can do what?
누가 무엇을 할 수 있나요?
Although you will know if you are caught
잡히면 알겠지만
Because alone, I don’t know anything anymore
혼자서는 더 이상 아무것도 모르니까
if you knew anyway
어쨌든 알고 있었다면
Although I don't want to share the responsibility of the police at all
경찰의 책임을 전혀 공유하고 싶지 않지만
So please let us not face each other again
그러니까 제발 우리 다시는 마주치지 말자
road..
도로..
Did it just disappear?
그냥 사라진 걸까요?
I am..
그래요..
Because I can't see much at night
밤에는 잘 안 보이거든요.
Too afraid of freedom
자유가 너무 무서워
Free is not paranoid
무료는 편집증이 아니다
anyone there?
거기 누구 없어요?
Even ran away
도망가기도 했고
I can't say I don't know anyone
아는 사람이 없다고는 말할 수 없어
Is the stranger’s reaction calm?
낯선 사람의 반응은 차분한가요?
Do not you remember?
기억나지 않나요?
Regardless of whether I said it myself or not
내가 직접 말했든 말든 상관없이
-Teacher- No, I'm not
-선생님- 아니요, 아니에요
why not?
왜 안 돼?
Does anyone blame Mrs. Li ?
리 부인을 비난하는 사람이 있나요 ?
The guy who ran away?
도망친 그 사람?
Do you know who that is?
그 사람이 누구인지 아시나요?
I do not know what to say
내가 무슨 말을 해야할지 모르겠어요
Ms. Li Zhuying
리 주잉 씨
Although I know it's hard to believe
알면서도 믿기 힘든 일
I'm trying to help Ms. Li now
나는 지금 Ms. Li를 도우려고 노력 중이야
telling the truth can stop it
진실을 말하면 막을 수 있다
threatened by someone
누군가로부터 위협을 받다
no matter what
무슨 일이 있어도
everything must be said
모든 것은 말해야 한다
-Lee Joo -young- Worry
-이주영 - 고민하다
But thank you for your concern
하지만 걱정해주셔서 감사해요
Really misunderstood
정말 오해받았어요
I'm treated like a human being
나는 인간처럼 대우받습니다.
no threat
위협은 없어
Relatives and elders will be worried
친척이나 어르신들이 걱정하실 텐데요.
Mr. Yin, can I come back?
인 씨, 다시 가도 될까요?
Wait a moment
잠깐만요
Come back for now
지금은 돌아와
Yun Yang, let’s go too
윤양아 나도 가자
Then see you at school tomorrow
그럼 내일 학교에서 봐요
Stay safe now..
이제 안심하세요..
Can I buy you your favorite bread and feed it to you?
당신이 좋아하는 빵을 사서 먹여도 될까요?
What are bread skewers?
빵 꼬치는 무엇입니까?
When you look at it, it's obvious that something is hidden
가만히 보면 뭔가 숨겨져 있는 게 뻔해
Is it because of this release?
이번 출시 때문일까요?
If that person is two days older than that person
그 사람이 그 사람보다 이틀 나이가 많다면
I don't think he knew what was going to happen.
나는 그가 무슨 일이 일어날지 몰랐다고 생각합니다.
Is this the home court?
여기가 홈 코트인가요?
(Tung Wah Tailor Shop)
(퉁와 양복점)
(in front of the inn)
(여관 바로 앞)
(Wujiang Hotel)
(우장 호텔)
(hostel)
(호스텔)
Are you here to see Beijin come back?
Beijin이 돌아오는 것을 보러 오셨나요?
I'm afraid there will be more questions that I don't know about
제가 모르는 질문이 더 많아질까봐
Is it possible?
가능합니까?
For all I know, tonight probably won't happen again
내가 아는 한, 오늘 밤은 아마도 다시는 일어나지 않을 것입니다
I don't know if this is the right answer
이게 정답인지는 모르겠는데
Because I don't know what you know and what you don't know
왜냐하면 나는 당신이 무엇을 알고 무엇을 모르는지 모르기 때문입니다.
That side might be the same
그 쪽도 마찬가지겠지
From now on we will learn about
지금부터 알아보겠습니다.
Let's go to the right place to talk
적당한 곳 으로 가서 얘기하자
(Bangbang Teahouse)
(방방찻집)
The race tilts slightly to the right
레이스가 약간 오른쪽으로 기울어져 있습니다.
tilt in this direction
이 방향으로 기울어져
- Teacher, look - Gin Clan leans to the left
- 선생님 보세요 - 진클랜이 왼쪽으로 기울어져 있어요
(Bangbang Teahouse)
(방방찻집)
Zuo Zuo
주오 주오
left
왼쪽
Last summer, he was struck down by lightning
지난 여름, 그는 벼락을 맞아 쓰러졌습니다.
If you view the fix now
지금 수정 사항을 보면
It's obvious that the owner doesn't care about the extent of his responsibility
소유자가 자신의 책임 범위에 관심이 없는 것은 분명합니다.
This is not a teahouse
이곳은 찻집이 아니다
You may already be familiar with this name
이미 이 이름이 익숙할 수도 있습니다.
This is the birthplace of useless matchsticks
이곳은 쓸모없는 성냥개비가 탄생한 곳 이다
I got it
알겠어요
(Bangbang Teahouse)
(방방찻집)
let's go now
이제 가자
I don't know if you already know, but this place
이미 알고 계실지는 모르겠지만 이곳은
In 1987, a serial murder case occurred in Wujiang
1987년 우장시 연쇄살인사건 발생
You may have guessed it, but I'm following this case
짐작하셨겠지만 저는 이 사건을 추적하고 있습니다 .
Did the detective do it?
형사가 그랬나요?
If you turn on the news, whether it's a weekend night or not
뉴스를 켜면 주말 밤이든 아니든
i think i remember
내 생각엔 기억나는 것 같아
A criminal?
범죄자?
The person who showed the photo to Ekan's reporter ?
에칸 기자에게 사진을 보여준 사람 ?
Wouldn't it be more logical to assume he was a news anchor ?
그가 뉴스 앵커라고 가정하는 것이 더 논리적이지 않을까요 ?
Oh, like this
아, 이렇게
Nine people in the TV series
TV 시리즈의 9명
Sorry for not watching the news much
뉴스를 많이 못봐서 죄송해요
Do you miss me too?
너도 내가 그리워?
No, it's not like that
아니요, 그렇지 않습니다.
I thought about all kinds of things
온갖 생각을 다 해봤어
Even if I'm stuck in life, I want to be safe
삶에 갇혀 있어도 안전하고 싶어
To get news?
뉴스를 얻으려면?
Roughly speaking, it is like this
대략적으로 말하면 이렇습니다
When will the case be heard?
사건 심리는 언제 이루어지나요?
Two days later, on the 14th
이틀 뒤인 14일
Two days later on the 16th
이틀 뒤인 16일
another case
또 다른 경우
A total of two girls died
총 2명의 소녀가 사망했습니다.
- No. 20.. - One of them is missing
- 20번.. - 한개 없어졌네요
I left a message
메시지를 남겼어요
Although I thought I ran away from home
집에서 도망친 줄 알았는데
actually dead
실제로 죽었어
What do you say now?
지금 뭐라고 말해요?
because he is dead
왜냐하면 그는 죽었으니까
There are three victims in total
피해자는 총 3명
During more than thirty years
삼십년이 넘는 세월 동안
No clues were found, let alone a body.
시체는커녕 단서도 발견되지 않았습니다.
Neither the police nor the victim’s family knew anything about it.
경찰도, 피해자 가족도 이 사실을 전혀 몰랐다.
How do you...
당신은 어떻게 ...
It's hard to believe but I'm here
믿기 ​​힘들지만 난 여기 있어
I tell you as written here
여기에 쓴 대로 말하노니
(people I killed)
(내가 죽인 사람들)
Please wait
기다리세요
Wuwei wrote
우웨이가 썼다
Madam, the article I wrote this time
부인, 제가 이번에 쓴 글은
Can't you give me a little taste?
좀 맛 좀 볼 수 없나요?
Can we say a confession?
고백을 해볼까요?
frank?
솔직한?
thirty years ago
30년 전
The perfect crime someone committed
누군가가 저지른 완전범죄
The person who starts the story is the protagonist
이야기를 시작하는 사람이 주인공이다
Spend the rest of my life learning it alone
남은 인생을 혼자 배우면서 보내세요
Is it a pity?
안타까운 일인가요?
So thirty years ago
그러니까 30년 전
I think it's about the same time as this novel.
이 소설과 거의 같은 시기인 것 같아요.
(small door)
(작은 문)
This time let’s talk about myself seriously.
이번에는 제 자신에 대해 진지하게 이야기해보겠습니다.
just kidding
농담이야
It's all written there
거기 다 써있어요
certainly
틀림없이
The teacher is really
선생님이 정말
I've been a teacher for a long time
나는 오랫동안 교사로 일해 왔습니다.
Editor
편집자
National American Award?
내셔널 아메리칸 어워드?
Thanks to this, Wu Guang’s new novel has not yet been published
덕분에 우광의 새 소설은 아직 출간되지 않았다.
i can hold
나는 붙잡을 수 있다
Even though I completely forgot about it after I got here
여기 오고 나서는 까맣게 잊어버렸는데도
After seeing that teacher just now
방금 그 선생님 뵙고 나서
Like seeing something weird every now and then
가끔씩 이상한 걸 보는 것처럼
I read it again
다시 읽었어
Same as the content in the novel
소설 내용과 동일
I don't think this is about what really happened.
나는 이것이 실제로 일어난 일에 관한 것이라고 생각하지 않습니다.
Anyway, that’s how it’s written
아무튼 그렇게 써있어요
Start with that school teacher
그 학교 선생님부터 시작해 보세요
three girls died
세 명의 소녀가 사망했습니다.
I didn't find the real culprit until the end
끝까지 진범을 찾지 못했다
This is about the real culprit, right?
이게 진짜 범인에 관한 이야기죠?
Last paragraph of second page, last line
두 번째 페이지의 마지막 문단, 마지막 줄
please confirm
확인 해주세요
"The truth was never revealed."
"진실은 밝혀진 적이 없습니다."
"He created all this death."
"그는 이 모든 죽음을 창조했습니다."
I am who I am
나는 나일 뿐이야
Even that fun fact
그 재미있는 사실조차
you are no longer in this house
당신은 더 이상 이 집에 없어요
really good
정말 좋다
(people I killed)
(내가 죽인 사람들)
Is it really five lights?
정말 조명이 다섯 개인가요?
In fact, I didn't find the real culprit
사실 진짜 범인은 못 찾았어요
I'm surprised
놀랐어요
Although the defendant ultimately refused
피고인은 결국 거절했지만
reality is unknowable
현실은 알 수 없다
Yes, that's why I talk like this
응, 그래서 내가 이렇게 얘기하는 거야
The first time I stole it from my mother
처음으로 엄마한테서 훔쳤어
it's really about him
정말 그 사람에 관한 거야
If so, this may be new evidence
그렇다면 이는 새로운 증거가 될 수도 있다.
can't say for sure
확실히 말할 수 없다
Anyway, this is a novel
아무튼 이거 소설이네
Even though it's based on a true story
실화를 바탕으로 한 작품임에도 불구하고
However, imagination can be very wild
그러나 상상력은 매우 거칠 수 있습니다.
I started this week...
이번주부터 시작했는데..
We cannot guarantee that this is a true representation of the Gowe Awards
우리는 이것이 Gowe Awards의 진정한 표현임을 보장할 수 없습니다.
I can't guarantee there won't be
없을 것이라고 보장할 수는 없습니다
Did you just see that?
방금 그거 봤어?
I also wrote about the whereabouts of the missing teacher
실종된 선생님 의 행방 에 대해서도 글을 썼습니다
someone who knows more than you
너보다 더 많이 아는 사람
Isn't this the culprit?
이 사람이 범인 아닌가요?
Because they are from the same village
같은 마을 출신이니까.
You can write down what you saw and heard at that time
그 때 보고 들은 것을 적어보면 된다
How many have I tried
나는 얼마나 많은 것을 시도했는가
Most are just official records
대부분은 공식 기록일 뿐
Why do you deny it?
왜 그것을 부정합니까?
Why do you make such clear accusations?
왜 그렇게 분명한 비난을 하는가?
Do you want Wu Mei to be the culprit?
Wu Mei가 범인이 되길 원하시나요?
Why so much knowledge...
지식이 왜이리 많은지...
That's why I doubt
그렇기 때문에 나는 의심한다.
Five lights, I know
불빛 다섯 개, 나도 알아
Because he is fully capable of doing so
그 사람은 충분히 그럴 능력이 있으니까.
What do you say now?
지금 뭐라고 말해요?
Are you talking about marrying me now?
지금 나랑 결혼하자고 말하는 거야?
pastor when
목사님 언제
What happened again?
또 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
What will you marry?
당신은 무엇과 결혼할 것인가?
we are not together yet
우리는 아직 함께 있지 않습니다
That guy who doesn't even taste like milk
우유 맛도 없는 그 사람
This is why I made mistakes early on
이래서 내가 일찍부터 실수를 했어
When will you actually be called out?
실제로 언제 호출됩니까?
-This time- Yin Ying
-이번에는- 음영
How is the child doing?
아이는 잘 지내나요?
Am I really going crazy because what did I do wrong?
내가 뭘 잘못해서 정말 미칠까?
- I've never said anything like that - Ma'am.
- 저는 그런 말을 한 적이 없습니다. - 부인.
A son and a daughter will be born and they will live well
아들과 딸이 태어나서 잘 살 것이다.
a son and a daughter
아들과 딸
- Sun Al - How's it going?
- 순알 - 잘 지내요?
Is there something wrong with your ears?
귀에 이상이 있는 걸까요?
When did I say they would leave?
내가 언제 그들이 떠날 것이라고 말했 습니까 ?
I just said I wanted to stay
난 그냥 머물고 싶다고 말했어
I asked what the dream was.
나는 꿈이 무엇인지 물었다.
I also want to have a family
나도 가족을 갖고 싶다
Sorry, I already have a partner
죄송합니다. 이미 파트너가 있습니다.
That’s why I can’t accept Hisoka’s heart
그래서 나는 히소카의 마음을 받아들일 수 없다.
- what is
- 무엇입니까?
Even if not, there will be a time when I can meet in front of you
아니더라도 언젠가는 네 앞에서 만날 수 있을 거야
Hey
여기요
It's really that person
정말 그 사람이에요
Sun Ai's boyfriend?
순아이의 남자친구요?
first love
첫사랑
Indeed, I came to speak
사실 말하려고 왔어
That's it
그게 다야
i hate flowers
나는 꽃을 싫어한다
keep great
잘 지내다
(Bom Bom Theater)
(봄봄극장)
Sun E
썬E
I guess I should explain what I just saw
방금 본 것을 설명해야 할 것 같아요
Need to explain slowly
천천히 설명해야지
Unless it's not...
그렇지 않은 이상...
family?
가족?
I have a son and a daughter
나는 아들 과 딸이 있습니다
I think this is my daughter's place
내 생각엔 여기가 내 딸의 집인 것 같아
Are you the daughter of suspect Bays?
당신은 용의자 베이스의 딸인가요?
bamboo
대나무
I'm scared
나 무서워
(hostel)
(호스텔)
How to call the police?
경찰에 어떻게 전화하나요?
Nothing to do with the police
경찰과는 아무 관련이 없습니다
I don't think I can stay here too long
여기 너무 오래 머물 수는 없을 것 같아
Excellent
훌륭한
Who really knows me?
나를 정말로 아는 사람은 누구인가?
Ok, I know
응 알아
(Someone is watching you)
(누군가가 당신을 지켜보고 있습니다)
Are you too confused?
너무 혼란스럽나요?
I was really shocked
정말 충격받았어요
It's hard to believe it's been thirty years since I was hit by a car
차에 치인 지 30년이 됐다는 게 믿기지 않아요.
The person who hits someone is a time traveler
사람을 때린 사람은 시간여행자다
In front of that man’s house, my mother’s family was all seated
그 사람 집 앞에는 우리 어머니 식구들이 다 앉아 있었는데
bamboo
대나무
Why do you really want to go to school?
정말로 학교에 가고 싶은 이유는 무엇입니까?
No
아니요
Why did you do that in the teahouse ?
찻집에서 왜 그랬어요 ?
it's a bit complicated
좀 복잡해요
To separate my parents in the teahouse
찻집에서 부모님을 분리시키려고
What will be divided?
무엇이 나누어질까요?
Don't let mom and dad see each other
엄마 아빠가 서로 만나지 못하게 하세요
from the sun...
태양으로부터...
- Acres? - What?
- 에이커? - 무엇?
Yes, everything is accidental
응, 모든 건 우연이야
I remember getting hit by a car without thinking twice.
두 번 생각할 것도 없이 차에 치인 기억이 납니다.
Stay in front of young parents
젊은 부모 앞에 머물다
Should I consider separating the two?
둘을 분리하는 것을 고려해야 할까요?
Have you never thought about the consequences of this?
이것의 결과에 대해 생각해 본 적이 없습니까?
- You can't come... - What's the matter?
- 넌 올 수 없어... - 무슨 일이야?
what happened
무슨 일이에요
What happened to those little guys?
그 작은 녀석들에게 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
Do I know nothing about this?
나는 이것에 대해 아무것도 모르는가?
One small action can change someone's entire future
하나의 작은 행동이 누군가의 미래 전체를 바꿀 수 있습니다
Did you tell me when you first came here ?
여기 처음 왔을 때 나한테 말했었나요 ?
So what is it?
그래서 그것은 무엇입니까?
before coming here
여기 오기 전에
I asked him what he was doing by the river
나는 그에게 강가에서 무엇을 하고 있는지 물었습니다.
(police)
(경찰)
That day at the river
그날 강에서
Mother abandoned us and left
어머니는 우리를 버리고 떠나셨다
no right to resent
원망할 권리는 없어
I abandoned my mother first
내가 먼저 엄마를 버렸어
because we don't know
우리는 모르기 때문에
I gave crazy love that I can't repay
갚을 수 없는 미친 사랑을 줬어
(Suen Er)
(수엔 어)
It's becoming a name that's crazy to ignore
무시하기엔 미친 이름이 되어가네
one day suddenly
어느날 갑자기
I don’t know if my mother understands
엄마가 이해하실지는 모르겠지만
There are too many moments that I can't look back on
돌이킬 수 없는 순간이 너무 많아
it's too late
너무 늦었어
That day, by the river, I had a strong desire
그 날 강가에서 나는 강한 열망을 품고 있었습니다
If there is only one chance
기회가 단 한 번뿐이라면
It would be nice if I could look back for a moment
잠시라도 돌아볼 수 있다면 좋을 텐데
I don't know if I look crazy
내가 미친 것처럼 보이는지 모르겠어
But actually, no matter what I do
그런데 사실 내가 뭘 하든
Until my mother went to the river
엄마가 강에 가실 때까지
If I think there's nothing I can do, I...
내가 할 수 있는 게 아무것도 없다고 생각하면 ...
I don't think I can bear it anyway
어차피 못 견딜 것 같아
Sorry, I didn't mean to say that
미안, 그런 말을 하려던 건 아니었는데
Come in
올
Just listen to it today
오늘은 한번 들어보세요
Excellent
훌륭한
I have to ask this
이건 물어봐야 해
Unless it's not
그렇지 않은 이상
That day at the river
그날 강에서
Mother abandoned us and left
어머니는 우리를 버리고 떠나셨다
(Bangbang Teahouse)
(방방찻집)
I don't think I picked this up
내가 이걸 선택한 ​​건 아닌 것 같아
(Women who study are more dangerous)
(공부하는 여자가 더 위험해요)
Really when and where?
정말 언제, 어디서요?
I stumbled upon this floating village on the banks of a river
나는 우연히 강둑에 떠 있는 이 마을을 발견했습니다.
pick it up without thinking
아무 생각 없이 집어들다
Why?
왜?
( Suspect in Wu Jong-il serial murder case )
( 우정일 연쇄살인사건 용의자 )
(Bangbang Teahouse)
(방방찻집)
Where did it come from?
그것은 어디에서 왔습니까?
There's something you need to know
당신이 알아야 할 것이 있습니다
(Wuzhengli Fishing Ground)
(우정리 어장)
Because of what I said yesterday
어제 내가 한 말 때문에
Don't worry
괜찮아요
This is my personal matter
이건 내 개인적인 문제야
Don't interfere with the work there
거기 일을 방해하지 마세요
For me, my mother is...
나에게 어머니는...
This is not a serious problem
이는 심각한 문제가 아닙니다.
He gave birth to me but never looked up
그 사람은 나를 낳았지만 한 번도 올려다보지 않았어
Because the one who ran away was my mother
도망친 건 우리 엄마였으니까
I don't quite understand how my mother feels
나는 어머니의 심정을 잘 이해하지 못한다.
As others have said, is there anything special and hurtful about it?
다른 분들 말대로 뭔가 특별하고 아픈 부분이 있나요?
i don't even know
나도 모르겠어
I never knew or didn't want to know
전혀 몰랐고 알고 싶지도 않았어
But no matter who
하지만 누구든지
I know the one I love has no reason, I don't know what it feels like
내가 사랑하는 사람에게는 이유가 없다는 걸 알아요, 어떤 느낌인지 모르겠어요
i don't care what happens
무슨 일이 일어나든 상관없어
The heart that misses my mother
엄마를 그리워하는 마음
Do you think your mother is not sensible enough?
네 엄마가 충분히 현명하지 않다고 생각하니?
what does that mean..
그게 무슨 뜻이야..
Knowing this, would you still make such a choice?
이런 사실을 알면서도 당신은 그런 선택을 하시겠습니까?
- What do you want to say now? - Listen carefully.
- 지금 하고 싶은 말이 무엇인가요? - 잘 들어보세요.
First murder tomorrow night
내일 밤 첫 살인
You know stuff will come out
뭔가 나올 줄 알잖아
matchbox
성냥갑
and the memorandum therein
그리고 거기에 적힌 메모
(Women who study are more dangerous)
(공부하는 여자가 더 위험해요)
this..
이것..
At that time, the police deliberately left the matter to the defendant
당시 경찰은 고의로 피고인에게 사건을 맡겼다.
They considered this mark
그들은 이 표시를 고려했습니다.
Among the second victim’s belongings
2차 피해자의 소지품 중
Because the same product comes out
같은 제품이 나오니까
Is that the mark?
그게 마크야?
So why is this...
그럼 이건 왜...
Why did the defendant use material from 34 years ago...
피고인은 왜 34년 전 자료를 사용했을까..
Will we meet again in 2021?
2021년에도 우리 다시 만날 수 있을까요?
This is a popular store
인기가 많은 매장이에요
Why on the bank of the river where your mother died?
왜 네 어머니가 돌아가셨던 강둑에 있는 거지?
Unless it's not...
그렇지 않은 이상...
no definite evidence
확실한 증거가 없다
Yes, your feelings are genuine
응, 너의 감정은 진심이야
Maybe your mother doesn't know
아마 엄마는 모르실 거예요
but if
하지만 만약에
if it's true
그것이 사실이라면
That day, by the river, your mother...
그날 강가에서 네 어머니는...
if you meet someone else
다른 사람 만나면
That was 34 years ago
그게 34년 전이야.
If the real culprit
진짜 범인이라면
So now you've made a mistake
그럼 이제 당신은 실수를 한 것입니다.
Do you hate yourself for giving up?
포기한 자신이 싫나요 ?
The person who can finally save my mother
드디어 엄마를 구할 수 있는 사람
do not you?
그렇지 않습니까?
Yun Yang
윤양
Were you too scared yesterday?
어제 너무 무서웠나요?
sorry
죄송합니다
I lied to you on purpose
일부러 거짓말을 했어
Basisu, it’s not just to meet that person.
바시스, 그 사람만 만나려고 그런 게 아니잖아.
Yes
예
Why did you miss this?
왜 이것을 놓쳤습니까?
Until she becomes a gray-haired grandma
백발 할머니가 될 때까지
I want to play with Yoongi forever
윤기랑 평생 놀고싶다
dear mother
친애하는 어머니
This is a letter, not a will
이건 유언장이 아니라 편지야
I will always be by your side
난 항상 당신 곁에있을 것입니다
My mom is always like this. .
우리 엄마는 항상 이런 식이에요. .
I just promised
방금 약속했어
How could it be misunderstood like this?
어떻게 이렇게 오해할 수 있겠습니까?
how so..
어떻게 그래..
Don't you understand in the end?
결국 이해 못하시나?
Yun Yang
윤양
Is that disappointment?
그게 실망인가요?
sorry
죄송합니다
What is always so painful?
항상 무엇이 그렇게 고통스럽습니까?
I do not understand
난 이해가 안 돼요
No, I really don't know either
아니, 나도 잘 모르겠어
It was written on a piece of paper taken from a matchbox
성냥갑에서 꺼낸 종이에 이렇게 쓰여 있었습니다.
They will have a common encounter
그들은 공통된 만남을 갖게 될 것이다
Don't worry
괜찮아요
more..
더..
Another such tragedy
또 다른 비극
I will protect it from happening
그런 일이 일어나지 않도록 지켜줄게
I will protect you no matter what
무슨 일이 있어도 너를 지켜줄게
But thanks anyway
하지만 어쨌든 고마워요
Is it that bad?
그렇게 나쁜가요?
Can't we have a cold drink together?
우리 같이 시원한 음료 한잔 할 수 없나요?
I didn't marry Fan Feng
나는 판펑과 결혼하지 않았다
Genlai, what are they doing?
겐라이, 저 사람들 뭐 하는 거야?
I have no idea
나는 전혀 모른다
I heard that the level was released, has Sun E's level dropped a lot?
레벨이 공개됐다고 들었는데, 선이의 레벨이 많이 떨어졌나?
- Thank you - Yes, do your job
- 감사합니다 - 네, 일을 하세요
- Teacher Che- Yes
- 채 선생님 - 네
Take it and eat it
받아서 먹어보세요
- I'll eat well. - Okay.
- 잘 먹겠습니다 - 알았어
- Yes , this is...
- 응 , 이건...
- Our son sent it from the United States.
- 네 - 우리 아들이 미국에서 보냈어요.
Oh America?
아 미국?
Doesn't it look great?
정말 좋아 보이지 않나요?
- This is... - Ha
- 이건... - 하하
I don’t know if it’s American, but something seems wrong.
미국산인지는 모르겠지만 뭔가 잘못된 것 같습니다.
- Did you notice? - Thanks
- 눈치채셨나요? - 감사해요
So now you've made a mistake
그럼 이제 당신은 실수를 한 것입니다.
Did you hate yourself and give up?
자신을 미워하고 포기 하셨나요 ?
Mother
어머니
good mom
좋은 엄마
No need to say it so strongly
그렇게 강하게 말할 필요는 없어
I need to say something sweet.
달콤한 말을 해야겠어요.
- Yes - Indeed, this country is huge
- 네 - 역시 이 나라는 넓군요
The country is big and the flowers are also big
나라는 크고 꽃도 크다
- The leaves are also big, very good - Yes
- 잎도 크고 아주 좋아요 - 네
- Hello - Yes, are you here?
- 안녕하세요 - 네, 여기 계세요?
I think so
그렇게 생각해요
It's time to throw this away
이제 이걸 버려야 할 때야
Why throw it away?
왜 버리나요?
Teacher Li Zhouying is here
Li Zhouying 선생님이 오셨습니다
14 hours flight to South Korea
한국까지 14시간 비행
Come on, cause I'll give you precious jelly
자, 소중한 젤리를 줄 테니까
Yes
예
I didn't tell anyone about last night
난 어젯밤에 대해 아무에게도 말하지 않았어
Go get it for me
가서 나한테 가져다 줘
gentlemen
신사
Jelly from America
미국에서 온 젤리
i will bring it
내가 가져올게
Thanks
감사해요
- Is it sweet? - come from America
- 달콤해요? - 미국에서 왔어요
come on now
지금 어서
- try this - thanks
- 시도해 보세요 - 감사합니다
- I'm depressed - I'm still the same
- 나 우울해 - 아직도 그대로야
- I think I'm going to get fat - Am I a bitch?
- 나 살찌는 것 같아 - 나 개년이야?
I answered a lot
대답을 많이 했어요
(Intermediate Lee Sun El, advanced class Gomizu)
(중급 이선엘, 고급반 고미즈)
- I can't believe it - I guess
- 믿을 수가 없어요 - 그런 것 같아요
step 1
1 단계
- Level 1 - His level is the same as before
- 레벨 1 - 레벨은 기존과 동일합니다.
I'm going back to class
나는 수업으로 돌아갈거야
- That's great. - Ma'am.
- 훌륭해요 - 부인
divine water
신성한 물
Is this enough?
이것이 충분하나요?
I am proud of you
난 너가 자랑 스럽다
How to get level?
레벨을 얻는 방법?
- School-wide level 1 - Ms.
- 학교 전체 레벨 1 - Ms.
The whole school is Level 1
학교 전체가 레벨 1입니다.
- Step 1 - Bamboo
- 1단계 - 대나무
- We are upgrading hahaha
- 업그레이드 중이에요 하하하
First level in the school
학교의 첫 번째 수준
I guessed most of it
대부분 짐작했겠지만
hehe
헤헤
Is it level one?
1레벨인가요?
I will be sad
나는 슬퍼 할 것이다
I'm very proud
나는 매우 자랑스럽다
Really?
정말?
Can you live with sad bad people?
슬픈 나쁜 사람들과 함께 살 수 있나요?
he came out
그는 나왔다
Pretend you can't pass the exam
시험에 합격하지 못한 척
Lee Seung-il always behaves like this
이승일은 항상 이런 행동을 한다
Are you that happy?
그렇게 행복해요?
Everyone can see it on the forehead
누구나 이마에서 그것을 볼 수 있다
Should I post it?
게시해야 하나요?
- Are you crazy? - Yin Ying
- 제정신이에요? - 인잉
This crazy Kim Hye Kyun
미친 김혜균이네
- Hey, you're in trouble. - Come on.
- 이봐요, 문제가 생겼군요 - 어서요
Qingxian
칭셴
Won't you come back soon?
곧 돌아오지 않을래?
- I hate it - I'm disappointed
- 싫다 - 실망스럽다
- how is he? - cool
- 그는 어때? - 시원한
- let's go - very disappointed
- 가자 - 매우 실망했어
bring back
다시 가져오다
(school rules)
(학교 규칙)
This school is weird
이 학교는 이상해요
it only sticks to the sides
옆면에만 붙어있어요
Do you like such a man?
당신은 그런 남자를 좋아합니까?
What do you really like to watch?
당신은 무엇을 보는 것을 정말로 좋아합니까?
(College Entrance Examination Part 1)
(대학 입시 1편)
This mathematical description can be used like this
이 수학적 설명은 다음과 같이 사용될 수 있습니다
Interesting
흥미로운
The whole school is suspicious
학교 전체가 의심스럽다
Please be conscious
의식해주세요
Mother
어머니
He is indeed a poor man
참으로 가난한 사람이로다
How is it going?
어떻게 지내요?
nothing
아무것도 아님
very good
매우 좋은
I don't want to lose my friendship
나는 우정을 잃고 싶지 않아요
Unless it's not...
그렇지 않은 이상...
Did something go wrong yesterday?
어제 무슨 일이 있었나요?
Even the flowers I gave you don’t work?
내가 준 꽃도 소용없나요?
what is that?
저게 뭐에요?
Why go through the trouble of choosing one yourself?
왜 스스로 하나를 선택하는 수고를 겪나요 ?
The one I bought is more beautiful
제가 산게 더 예뻐요
indeed
물론
take it
가져
Girls don't like it very much because it's naive
순진해서 여자들이 별로 안 좋아함
is that so?
그렇습니까?
so
그래서
Who will open it?
누가 열까요?
Are you really not going to tell me?
정말 나한테 말 안 할 거야?
Hey, that's it...
이봐, 그게 다야...
I'll tell you if I can
할 수 있으면 말해줄게
I know, try it
알아요, 한번 해보세요
Thanks
감사해요
- Tried it with Su Shui - Yeah
- 소수이와 함께 해봤 어 - 네
He said it was a flower
꽃이라고 하더군요
Your ho...what?
네 여자... 뭐?
Do girls like it?
여자애들이 좋아하니?
I'm sure
확실해
Although he says he doesn't always like it
그는 항상 그것을 좋아하지는 않는다고 말하지만
This is what it means to like
좋아한다는 건 이런 뜻이야
pretend to be shy
수줍은 척하다
If you don’t like it, you just don’t like it. Why do you feel ashamed?
싫으면 그냥 싫은거인데 왜 부끄러움을 느끼나요?
Hey, so just give me a flower
야, 그럼 나한테 꽃 하나만 줘
Give me a flower, where is the rest?
꽃을 주세요. 나머지는 어디에 있나요?
Oh, is that right?
아, 그렇죠?
Well, that too. .
글쎄, 그것도. .
I use it in a good place
좋은 곳에 사용하고 있어요
Hello
안녕하세요
Why do you think this is not Gotsu?
왜 이것이 Gotsu가 아니라고 생각합니까?
If this place is the culprit
만약 이곳이 범인이라면
34 years later, another murder
34년 뒤 또 다른 살인
This is why my mother died
이래서 엄마가 죽었어
I think the defendant may be more of a backlighter
내 생각엔 피고인이 역광에 더 가깝다고 생각해요
It's entirely possible
전적으로 가능합니다
but..
하지만..
The man who chased the school teacher and ran away last night
어젯밤 학교 선생님을 쫓아다니다 도망친 남자
Who is the one?
그 사람은 누구입니까?
I think this is the one I've been waiting for
내 생각엔 이게 내가 기다려온 바로 그 사람인 것 같아
at the same time
동시에
I thought there would be answers on Lee Joo Young's path and waited
이주영의 길에는 답이 있을 거라 생각하고 기다렸다
Lee Joo Young’s route on the night he was killed
이주영이 살해된 날 밤의 루트
(Let us move forward with freedom, creativity and wisdom)
( 자유와 창의, 지혜로 전진 하자)
The person who got off work that night was Lee Joo-young
그날 밤 퇴근한 사람은 이주영이었다.
I left school around ten o'clock
나는 10시쯤에 학교를 떠났다
(Wuzhong Middle School)
(우중중학교)
(Bangbang Teahouse)
(방방찻집)
destination..
목적지..
This is the Bom Bom teahouse we went to yesterday
어제 갔던 봄봄 찻집이에요
welcome
환영
There are twenty minutes and half past ten
20분 10시 30분이 있어요
Lee Joo Young is out
이주영이 빠졌네
The next destination is definitely Wuzheng Inn
다음 목적지 는 당연히 Wuzheng Inn
But that night, I couldn't go to Lee Joo Young's hotel
그런데 그날 밤 나는 이주영의 호텔에 갈 수 없었다.
(pay phone)
(공중전화)
(Wujiang Hotel)
(우장 호텔)
(Bangbang Teahouse)
(방방찻집)
From teahouse to hotel , even if it’s a step slower
찻집에서 호텔까지 한걸음 더디더라도
only thirty minutes
고작 30분
Just disappeared in such a short distance
그렇게 짧은 거리에서 그냥 사라졌어
Until he was found dead the next day
다음날 숨진 채로 발견될 때까지
Are there no witnesses within such a short distance ?
그렇게 가까운 거리에 목격자는 없나요 ?
No one saw who he met at the same time
그가 누구를 동시에 만났는지 본 사람은 아무도 없었습니다.
That's why I didn't watch it myself
그래서 내가 직접 보지는 않았어
Same time and same place
같은 시간 같은 장소
towards one direction
한 방향을 향해
Because I will stand behind Lee Joo Young
이주영 뒤에 내가 서 있을테니까
So maybe we'll see the man in the blue hat again
그럼 파란 모자를 쓴 남자를 다시 보게 될지도 모르지
Blue hat?
파란색 모자?
Lee Joo Young’s 20 Minutes in the Teahouse
이주영의 찻집에서의 20분
He was the only person I met there
그 사람은 내가 거기서 만난 유일한 사람이었어
(Bangbang Teahouse)
(방방찻집)
Is this an argument?
이것이 논쟁입니까?
Although he is a very suspicious person
그 사람이 의심이 많은 사람이긴 하지만
At that time, the police were unable to fully investigate who it was.
당시 경찰은 그가 누구인지 충분히 조사할 수 없었다.
But the guy I chased last night was wearing a blue hat
그런데 어젯밤에 내가 쫓던 그 남자는 파란 모자를 쓰고 있었어
The National American Awards have not been completely cancelled.
National American Awards는 완전히 취소되지 않았습니다.
will be fully considered and monitored
충분히 고려하고 모니터링할 예정입니다.
but..
하지만..
As for Gomisu, I still need it
고미수는 아직 필요해요
I'll catch Mion carefully here
여기서는 미온을 조심히 잡을 게
1987 and 2021
1987년과 2021년
That man can't kill anyone
그 사람은 사람을 못 죽여
Because I'm here to do this
왜냐면 난 이걸 하려고 여기 왔으니까
So please trust me and wait
그러니 저를 믿고 기다려주세요.
Miss Yu Fan
미스 유 팬
(Confident freedom)
(자신감 있는 자유)
(Let us unite as one nation through cooperation)
(협력을 통해 하나의 민족으로 뭉치자)
I'll come back to make sure it's safe
안전한지 확인하러 다시 올게요
Shall we go together?
같이 갈래?
The work I have to do is neither ordinary nor special.
내가 해야 할 일은 평범하지도 특별하지도 않다.
and then
그런 다음
Don't go alone, go with your mom and uncle
혼자 가지 말고 엄마, 삼촌과 함께 가세요
(Cream Twisted Jelly)
(크림 트위스트 젤리)
Let's go with Yoon Young
윤영이랑 같이 가자
american jelly
아메리칸 젤리
(Detective Division 1)
(탐정1과)
misunderstanding
오해
I was not chased or threatened by anyone
나는 누구에게도 쫓기거나 위협받지 않았다
They must be hiding something
뭔가 숨기고 있는 게 틀림없어
Are you going to buy your favorite rolls?
좋아하는 롤을 사러 갈 건가요?
I know I'm following
내가 팔로우하고 있다는 걸 알아요
I let myself hear these words on purpose
일부러 이런 말을 듣게 했어
It seems to be telling the woman that she is in a dangerous situation
여자에게 위험한 상황에 처해 있음을 알려주는 것 같다.
Yes
예
Brother, where are you going?
형님, 어디 가시나요?
- Not that bad - So why eat them all?
- 나쁘지 않아요 - 그럼 왜 다 먹나요?
Hey badminton number eight
안녕하세요 배드민턴 8번
Where are you going alone?
혼자 어디로 가시나요?
(Wujiang Police Station)
(우장 경찰서)
confirm
확인하다
Why not reconfirm?
왜 재확인하지 않습니까?
Like the hospital manager again, he broke the pot
또 병원장처럼 냄비를 깨뜨렸어
If you didn't bring it
안 가져오셨다면
Please stop, eight hundred knees
제발 그만둬 팔백무릎아
Yes, there is a new teacher at Goi High School
네, 고이고등학교에 새로운 선생님이 오셨습니다
Things are a little weird, so I'll be back
상황이 좀 이상해서 다시 올게요
Hey
여기요
What's weird?
뭐가 이상해요?
Don’t you know who the eldest brother is?
큰 형이 누군지 모르세요?
(in front of the inn)
(여관 바로 앞)
(Wuzhong Hotel)
(우중 호텔)
That school teacher has three old crimes
그 학교 선생님은 세 가지 오래된 범죄를 저질렀어요
We just pretend not to know
우린 그냥 모른 척해
He said he was not an ordinary person
자기는 보통 사람이 아니라고 하더군요
Tonight
오늘 밤
If nothing else changes, tonight
아무것도 변하지 않는다면
Is it really not helpful?
정말 도움이 안 되는 걸까요?
Since it's my business, I can do anything
내 일이니까 뭐든지 할 수 있어
Because I'm used to moving alone
혼자 움직이는 게 익숙해서
What if something changes?
뭔가 바뀌면 어떡하지?
Go first
먼저가
- Hello
- 안녕하세요
- Hello yes
- 안녕하세요 네
business card
명함
- take a look - hello
- 좀 보세요 - 안녕하세요
How is this going?
어떻게 되어가나요?
- Hello - Yeah
- 네
- Hello
- 안녕하세요
I asked what happened
무슨 일이냐고 물었더니
I'm talking about removing it
없애라는 얘기인데
Make sure you work hard for about a month
한달정도 열심히 해주세요
The opportunity has been given
기회가 주어졌습니다
Aren’t you here to help Li Zhouying?
Li Zhouying을 도우러 온 게 아닌가요?
For such people, you have to help, right?
그런 분들은 도와줘야겠죠?
I?
나?
Mr. Yin Haijun
인하이준 씨
You might even die because of that woman
그 여자 때문에 죽을 수도 있어
do you know?
당신은 알고 있나요?
Hey, let's go grab it, don't miss it
야, 잡으러 가자 놓치지 말고
- Yes, let's go.
- 응, 가자
ha
하아
leg
다리
Why so fast?
왜 그렇게 빠른가요?
tired
피곤한
If I really only paid 500,000 won, I would ask a Korean lady to do it
진짜 50만원만 냈으면 한국 아줌마한테 해달라고 했을텐데
They said it belonged to my father
그건 내 아버지의 것이라고 하더군요
strength..
힘..
There will only be half a million
50만개만 있을거에요
Even if you give five million, it is absolutely impossible
500만 줘도 절대 불가능
Korean wife, that little girl
한국인 아내, 그 어린 소녀
My daughter, what is going on?
내 딸아, 무슨 일이야?
Father
아버지
The daughter is Yu Zaili’s Genshun
딸은 유자이리의 겐슌
Is it the same now?
지금도 마찬가지인가요?
what happened
무슨 일이에요
Even Chestnut smiled, poor child
체스트넛도 웃었다 불쌍한 아이야
really annoyed
정말 짜증나
- Mom - I'm going to Seoul
- 엄마 - 나 서울에 갈 거예요
When is the fastest bus?
가장 빠른 버스는 언제입니까?
I was shocked
나는 충격 받았다
Will be there in five minutes
5분 안에 도착할 거예요
- Give me a ticket. - A ticket?
- 티켓 주세요 - 티켓요?
Wait a moment
잠깐만요
- Ha - let's see.
- 하 - 어디 보자.
Give it quickly
빨리 줘
Why are they all running around sweating ?
왜 다들 땀을 흘리며 뛰어다니는 걸까요?
What
무엇
- Ha - Wait a minute, teacher.
- 하 - 잠깐만요 선생님.
arrest him
그를 체포하다
Where does the otter come from to give the orders?
수달은 어디서 명령을 내리나요?
- Ah Nuttle - But I listen
- 아 너틀 - 하지만 난 들어요
-let go
- 가자
let it go
놔둬
-Miss -Teacher
-미스 -선생님
- Let go - just for a moment
- 놓아주세요 - 잠시만요
-Teacher, wait a minute - let go
- 선생님, 잠깐만요 - 놔주세요
please
제발
I don't know why I do this
내가 왜 이런 짓을 하는지 모르겠어
I have to stay here tonight
오늘 밤은 여기에 머물러야 해요
Only then can you catch it
그래야만 잡을 수 있다
It will be like this
이렇게 될 것이다
Korean teachers also came
한국인 선생님도 오셨어요
Mother
어머니
- You two - Lee Joo Young
- 너희 둘 - 이주영
Do you think I don't know you are watching me every night?
당신이 매일 밤 나를 지켜보고 있다는 걸 내가 모를 것 같나요?
That night he found me under the bridge
그날 밤 그는 다리 밑에서 나를 발견했어요
Isn't it a coincidence?
우연이 아닌가?
hand it over to the police
경찰에 넘겨주세요
It was planned from the beginning
처음부터 계획된 일이었어
Now I misunderstood something
지금 내가 뭔가를 오해하고 있었어
Please calm down and give me that knife
진정하고 그 칼 좀 주세요
i don't trust anyone
난 누구도 믿지 않아
dirty spy
더러운 스파이
please believe my words
내 말을 믿어주세요
us..
우리를..
I'm doing this to help Lee Joo Young
이주영을 도우려고 이러는 거야
What's the matter, ma'am?
무슨 일이에요, 부인?
release
풀어 주다
please lee juyoung
이주영 부탁해요
Please raise your voice because the police are coming
경찰이 오고 있으니 목소리를 높여주세요
Is there no place to hide, father?
숨을 곳은 없나요 아버지?
here, here, inside
여기, 여기, 내부
go in
들어가다
How are you? No injuries?
어떻게 지내세요? 부상은 없나요?
I am fine
괜찮아요
Yes
예
i don't know how to speak
나는 어떻게 말하는지 모르겠어요
The bus has left. Who are you talking about?
버스가 떠났어요 누구를 말하는 겁니까?
We here have been talking about Miss Korea
지금까지 미스코리아에 대해 이야기해 왔습니다.
Hello
안녕하세요
You said it's impossible, you bad guy
불가능하다고 했잖아 나쁜놈아
The father said, my daughter is Oh Jae-ri Geun-soon
아버지는 내 딸이 오재리 근순이라고 했다.
Let’s check the accommodation again
숙소를 다시 확인해 볼까요
- Pastor Yes - Yes, I know.
- 목사님 네 - 네, 알겠습니다.
- Ha - A gift from my father, bad girl.
- 하 - 아버지가 주신 선물, 나쁜 여자.
Why..
왜..
all because of me
다 나 때문이야
I misjudged the changes
변경사항을 잘못 판단했습니다.
In any case, it would be too risky to send him back to the inn tonight.
어쨌든, 오늘 밤에 그를 여관으로 돌려보내는 것은 너무 위험할 것입니다.
Yes, take them to a safe place first
네, 먼저 안전한 곳으로 데려가세요
I thought I was alone
혼자인 줄 알았는데
I'm scared
나 무서워
sorry
죄송합니다
Is it really okay to go alone?
정말 혼자 가도 괜찮나요?
Just look at this face and I'll be back
이 얼굴만 보면 내가 돌아올게
(Bom Bom Tea House Coffee and Tea)
(봄봄티하우스 커피와 차)
if you are lucky
운이 좋다면
Even without Lee Joo Young
이주영이 없어도
at the same time and the same place
같은 시간, 같은 장소
I wonder if that person will come out
그 사람이 나올까 궁금해
if you are lucky
운이 좋다면
that face
저 얼굴
Continue to confirm
계속해서 확인하세요
that person..
저 사람..
Because 34 years later, I will be the one responsible for killing my mother.
34년 뒤에는 어머니를 죽인 책임은 나 자신이 될 것이기 때문이다.
Going crazy
미쳐가네
(Women who study are more dangerous)
(공부하는 여자가 더 위험해요)
"A Stranger I Met"
"내가 만난 낯선 사람"
one of the three suspects
세 명의 용의자 중 한 명
hidden blue hat
숨겨진 파란색 모자
Everything matches the action
모든 것이 행동과 일치합니다
The most likely culprit is Bakhisu
범인은 바키수일 가능성이 가장 높다
If the blue hats are the real culprits
파란 모자가 진짜 범인이라면
His mother...
그의 어머니...
i killed my wife
내가 아내를 죽였어
The blue hat is yours...
파란 모자는 당신의 것입니다 ...
I know, I saw it with my own eyes
알아, 난 내 눈으로 봤어
Although I never thought of becoming such a person
그런 사람이 될 생각은 없었지만
just be one of the skeptics
그냥 회의론자 중 하나가 되세요
Is the blue hat talking about my father now?
파란 모자가 지금 우리 아버지에 대해 말하는 걸까요?
what happened
무슨 일이에요
impossible
불가능한
(appendix)
(부록)
How to do this...
이를 수행하는 방법 ...
how..
어떻게..
This kind of action has been done before
이런 종류의 작업은 이전에도 수행되었습니다.
stay away
떨어져있어
(Bangbang Teahouse)
(방방찻집)
"A Stranger I Met"
"내가 만난 낯선 사람"